Guide to the Paper Tiger Television Records MSS.276
Fales Library and Special Collections
Paper Tiger Television Records
1968-2017
Fales Library and Special Collections
Paper Tiger Television Collective (Firm)
MSS.276
187.9 Linear Feet in 146 record cartons, 35 oversize folders, 22 box binders, 17 flat boxes, 15 manuscript boxes, 11 cassette boxes, 10 upright video containers, 3 card boxes, 2 LP boxes, and 1 serials box.
2.71 Gigabytes in 873 files.
4 websites in 4 archived websites.
1100 U-matic
369 MiniDV
229 VHS
131 Hi8
47 Betacam_SP
16 1_Inch_Video_Reel
13 Betacam
7 S-VHS
4 Digital_Betacam
3 DVCAM
1 Betamax
1 audiocassette
Paper Tiger Television is a New York-based video collective founded in 1981. Their public access programming critiques media, culture, and politics. The Paper Tiger Television Records contain video recordings, paper materials, and born-digital materials documenting the organization's television productions, administrative activities, participation in events, publicity, financial management, political advocacy, and relationships with other independent media organizations.
Conditions Governing Access
Repository permission is required for access to some materials in Series IV. Please contact Fales Library and Special Collections, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Paper Tiger Television Archive was donated to NYU's Fales Library by the Paper Tiger Television Collective in 2010. Accretions were donated in 2016 by Julie Ludwig, Paper Tiger Television, and in 2018 by Marisa Holmes. Further accretions were donated in 2019.
http://papertiger.org/, http://blog.papertiger.org/, and http://papertigertv.blogspot.com/ were initially selected by Tamiment curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in circa 2007-2009 as part of the Alternative Mass Media / News Web Sites Web Archive. In November 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2015, these seeds were transferred to the Fales Library. In 2018, http://weinterruptthisprogram.org/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2019.057.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Appraisal
In March 2025, 88 linear feet of audiovisual materials were deaccessioned, including duplicate videos and commercial videos; 2 linear feet of paper materials were deaccessioned, including sensitive financial documents and employee records; and 10 computer discs were deaccessioned, including copyrighted materials, sensitive employee documents, and proprietary computer programs.
In July 2025, 3 U-matic tapes and 6 MiniDV tapes were deaccessioned due to duplicative content.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in eight series, with Series II, III, VI, and VII arranged into subseries. The arrangement is as follows:
Series I. Administrative Files, arranged alphabetically
Series II. Activities, arranged alphabetically
Subseries II.A Programming
Subseries II.B Exhibits and Installations
Subseries II.C Workshops and Conferences
Subseries II.D Film Festivals and Screenings
Series III. Publicity, arranged alphabetically
Subseries III.A Press
Subseries III.B Promotion
Series IV. Financial Material, arranged chronologically
Series V. Posters and Maps, arranged alphabetically
Series VI. Photographs, arranged alphabetically
Subseries VI.A Show Stills
Subseries VI.B Installations and Events
Subseries VI.C Office, Party, and Youth Program Snapshots
Series VII. Video Productions, arranged chronologically
Subseries VII.A Broadcast Videos
Subseries VII.B Non-Broadcast Videos
Series VIII. Objects, arranged alphabetically
Series IX. Archived Websites
Historical Note
Paper Tiger Television is a New York-based public access video collective. Co-founded by DeeDee Halleck in 1981, Paper Tiger TV was the first nationally distributed public access television program. Its programming critiques media corporatization and censorship, covering issues such as racism, sexism, economic inequality, and U.S. imperialism. Episodes often follow the format of a guest scholar reading and critiquing a piece of mainstream media, such as Paper Tiger TV's earliest programs featuring Herb Schiller critiquing The New York Times. Frequent guests include Herb Schiller, Brian Winston, Tuli Kupferberg, Noam Chomsky, Amy Goodman, and Joel Kovel.
In 1986, Paper Tiger TV founded Deep Dish Television, the first grassroots satellite network in the United States. From 1986 to 2018, Deep Dish TV produced work by independent videomakers, programmers, and social activists on a variety of cultural and political topics. Deep Dish TV collaborated with Paper Tiger TV on the Gulf Crisis TV Project, a ten-part series exploring many aspects of the Gulf War.
In addition to being broadcasted nationally on public access channels, Paper Tiger's programs have been shown internationally in screenings and installations. Installations in this collection include "Dream House" at the Wexner Center for the Arts, 1991; "Smashing Myths of the Information Age" at the San Francisco Art Institute, 1992; and the "Being the Media: Designing a New Rrradical Media" Conference in New York, 2012.
Paper Tiger TV has a history of advocacy in and outside of their television programming. Members of the collective have organized workshops and programs, distributed educational resources on video production, and collaborated with youth in New York City to produce programs such as "Homecoming Queens" (1999), "Access Orbit" (2001), "Biorhythms" (2002), "On the Real" (2002), "War and the Economy" (2002), and "Basta Ya!" (2010). Paper Tiger has also continuously advocated for public access programming, and has long standing relationships with other independent media organizations such as the Manhattan Neighborhood Network, Democracy Now!, and the Alliance for Community Media.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to some audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Audiovisual materials that have not been preserved may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Fales Library and Special Collections, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596, with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Related Materials
The Deep Dish TV Records, MSS.312
Scope and Contents
The Paper Tiger Television Records (1968-2017) contain video recordings, paper materials, photographs, and born-digital materials documenting the organization's television productions, administrative activities, participation in events, publicity, financial management, political advocacy, and relationships with other independent media organizations.
This collection documents the day-to-day operations of Paper Tiger TV, including administrative files such as meeting minutes, training materials, lease agreements, and correspondence; financial documents such as grant applications, budget reports, receipts, invoices, and donor files; and photographs of office activities and collective members.
Paper Tiger TV's participation in events, such as exhibitions, conferences, workshops, screenings, and film festivals, is represented in this collection in ephemera, such as flyers, postcards, schedules, and posters; planning documentation, including correspondence, timelines, budgets, and floor plans; video recordings used in installations; and photographs and video recordings of event proceedings.
Publicity for Paper Tiger TV's programming and activities in this collection includes published articles and advertisements, as well as promotional materials such as ephemera, outreach materials, graphic design, outreach to viewers, and promotional videos.
The majority of this collection documents Paper Tiger TV's television productions from 1981-2014. Video recordings include broadcast and distribution masters of programs, as well as dubs, production elements, various edits of programs, and source material such as unedited footage of events and interviews. Production files, found in Series II.A, include correspondence and contracts with partner organizations, meeting minutes, budgets, project proposals, submissions, scripts, cue cards, research files, and viewer feedback on programs. The collection also includes objects used in production, such as props, banners, clothing, "crankees" (hand-painted scrolls used to display credits in videos), and backdrops.
Public Access Television -- New York.; Television broadcasting -- United States.; Alternative mass media -- United States; Mass media criticism -- United States; Feminism and mass media.; Documentary television programs.; Politics and government -- Television programs.; AIDS (Disease) and mass media.; Persian Gulf War, 1991.; Audiocassettes.; Videocassettes.; Photographs.; Props (object genres); Printed ephemera.; Paper Tiger Television Collective (Firm); Deep Dish TV Network; Democracy Now! (Organization); Halleck, DeeDee
- Series I. Administrative Files, 1979-2016; 14 Linear Feet in 10 record cartons, 3 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize folders, 2 cassette boxes, 1 card box, and 1 flat box.; 4 U-matic; 2 VHS; 1 MiniDV; 1 Hi8; 1.70 Megabytes in 35 files.
  Scope and Content
  Series I. Administrative Files (1979-2016) contains documentation of Paper Tiger TV's administrative activities, including lease agreements; membership files for professional organizations; mailing lists; release forms and licensing contracts; internal and external correspondence; meeting minutes and agendas; staff and board retreat proceedings; training materials and job descriptions; and documentation of preservation measures.
  Arrangement
  Series I. Administrative Files (1979-2016) is arranged alphabetically.
  - 911 Emergency Employment Clearing House, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A.J. Muste, Paper Tiger Retreat, Fire, Pond sounds, June 15, 2008 (Box 183, Minidv 276_1263)
  - A.J. Muste Memorial Institute -- Lease Agreements, 1986 (Box 102, Folder 19)
  - A.J. Muste Memorial Institute -- Peace Pentagon, 2007-2013 (Box 102, Folder 20-21)
  - A.J. Muste Memorial Institute -- Sheltering Grants, 2008-2011 (Box 102, Folder 22)
  - Access Meeting #1 -- Diana Agosta, Karen Rogoff, Judy Escolono, Sean Caulomusto, June 13, 1989
    - Camera 1, Part 1 (Box 72, U-matic 276_0280)
    - Camera 1, Part 2 (Box 72, U-matic 276_0281)
    - Camera 2, Part 1 (Box 72, U-matic 276_0278)
    - DCTV (Box 123, Vhs 276_0873)
  - Access Meeting #2 -- Lilian Jimenez, DeeDee Halleck, Vicky Gholson, June 20, 1989
    - Camera 1, Part 1 (Box 72, U-matic 276_0279)
    - Camera 2 Master (Box 105, Vhs 276_0559)
  - Access Orbit -- Binder, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Access Orbit -- Survey, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Activist Group contact list, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Activism info - miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Agenda, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Agendaaaa, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alliance for Community Media, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alliance for Community Media -- Affiliate Member Recruitment Kit, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Alternative Communication Strategies in Third World Countries", 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Film Institute -- Logs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Anti-war movement, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Apple Bytes - NYV - ITP [layout of computer icons], 1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Artist Residence - call for applications, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Association of Independent Video and Filmmakers (AIVF) -- Event board, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 15, 16, 17)
  - Association of Independent Video and Filmmakers (AIVF) -- Membership, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 18, Box 98, Folder 1)
  - B's Study of PTTV -- Proposal (Berit Nilsen Bua), Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - BFVF Satellite -- Proposal, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bicycle Tour, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Book proposal, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Brainlink / ISP info, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Brand Positioning for Nonprofits" guide, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Broadband Service, 2002-2006 (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Bronxnet public access files, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "Budgeting for Grant Proposals" guide, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Case covers, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28-30)
  - Cathy Scott's file, Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Cherry Tree Association newsletter, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Clippings -- Big corporations, Undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Clippings -- Business Week, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Clippings -- CIA, Undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Clippings -- Gender and social roles, Undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Clippings -- IMF, Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Clippings -- Newspapers and the press, Undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Collage -- Rudy Giuliani, Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Collateral Damage -- Brown U. Contract, Undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Communications issues, Undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Contract -- Consultants, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Contracts / Releases, Undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Contract -- WTO: Free Speech TV, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Copyright -- Library of Congress application, Undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence -- Access Orbit Thank Yous, Random groups we've approved, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence -- Alternative publications, Undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence -- Cathy Scott, Undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence -- Dan Marcus, Undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence -- DeeDee Halleck, Undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence -- Fan postcards and letters, Undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence -- Fanmail, Undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence -- General, Undated (Box 1, Folder 56-57)
  - Correspondence -- Gulf Crisis TV Project, Undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence -- Linda Iannacone, Undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence -- Media / Political organizations, Undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence -- Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence -- PTTV San Francisco, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence -- Postcards, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence -- PBS, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence -- Randi Cecchine, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence -- Support letters, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Curriculum Guide -- "Graphics" folder, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Curriculum Vita -- Michael Eisenmenger, c. 1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - DeeDee Halleck -- Public Broadcasting, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Deep Dish TV -- Board Retreat, Immigrants Rights Rally, May, 1997 (Box 188, Hi8 276_1576)
  - Deep Dish TV -- Call for tapes, "The Nation Erupts", 1992 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Deep Dish TV -- Contact list for Gulf Crisis TV Project, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Deep Dish TV -- Correspondence, 1991-2004; FA_MSS_276_ER_1
  - Deep Dish TV -- Directory, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Deep Dish TV -- Member list, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "The Discreet Art of the Bourgeoisie" -- The Nation, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Distribution Agreement, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Distribution Contract -- AIMN and ITF, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Distribution Contracts, 2003-2014 (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Distribution possibilities, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - DIVA TV Press Pass, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Diversity training -- Board notes, Undated (Folder 36)
  - Diversity training materials, Undated (Box 4, Folder 31-32)
  - Drugs and Medicine subject file, Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Duplication services, Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Employee Policy Handbook, circa 1998 (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - Equipment Manuals, 1981-1991 (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Felix Survey, Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Film images -- Hollywood, etc..., Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Flyer and newspaper clippings, Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Form letters, Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Forms -- Masters, Undated (Box 2, Folder 24A)
  - "Free Radio in Japan" by Tetsuo Kogawa, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Free Speech TV -- Invoices, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Free Speech TV -- Licensing Agreements, Undated (Box 2, Folder 27-28)
  - Freedom of Information, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - French and Dutch Video -- Cinema Action, Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Fundraiser Files -- Freedom of information request, Undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Fundraiser Files -- Fundraisers, Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - General Admin. binder, Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Graphics and images, Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Gulf Crisis TV Project -- Articles, Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Hands Off! War Resisters League booklet, Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Hanging cards with tiger pictures, Undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Health insurance research, Undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - "Hey Hobbes, What's a Paper Tiger?" cartoon, Undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - History of police brutality in the Latino community -- research file, Undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Holiday party invitations, Undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Independent Media Distribution Alliance, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Intern log book, Undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - International media communications -- subject file, Undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - IMF - World Bank, Undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - International public access listing, Undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Internship info, Undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Internship program, 2006-2014 (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - Inventory, storage space, Undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Invoice list, Undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Invoice and phone codes, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Invoices -- Girls Inc., Undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Invoices -- Japanese visitors, Undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Invoices -- Lower East Side Girls Club, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Job announcements, Undated (Box 2, Folder 56-57)
  - Jobs Committee, 1998-2001 (Box 2, Folder 58, Box 98, Folder 7)
  - Job descriptions, misc., Undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Job file, Undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Jobs / Resumes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Ken Ives -- "Caña Amarga", Undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - "Krieg" exhibit subject file, Austria, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - La Voz Popular -- Notes and materials, Undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Libraries for the Future -- Telecom Toolbox, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Licensing agreements, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Lightworks -- Access Orbit, Policy stuff, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - List of mentions in publications, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - List of public access stations, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Los Angeles -- Mailing lists, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Mailing Lists, 1996; FA_MSS_276_ER_2
  - Mailing Lists -- Additions, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Mailing Lists -- Address corrections, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Mailing Lists -- Forms and requests, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Mailing Lists -- Fundraiser files, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Mailing Lists -- Guest book, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Mailing Lists -- Gulf Crisis TV Project, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Mailing Lists -- LA Outreach, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 12A)
  - Mailing Lists -- Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Mailing Lists -- Organizational research, 2000-2003 (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
  - Mailing Lists -- Press, Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Mailing Lists -- Sign up forms, undated (Box 3, Folder 18, Box 98, Folder 8)
  - Mailing Lists -- Tape lists, Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Mailing Lists --"To enter", Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Mailing Lists -- VHS distribution, Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Malcolm X Grassroots Movement -- Info sheet, Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Manhattan Neighborhood Network -- Control Room Guide, 2004 (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - Manhattan Neighborhood Network -- Scheduling Forms, 2006-2014 (Box 99, Folder 11)
  - Materials for the Arts, Undated (Box 3, Folder 23 - 24)
  - Materials for the Arts Donations, 2007 (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - Media Alliance Newsletter -- Communications arts, Undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Media Network Meeting, 1996; FA_MSS_276_ER_3
  - Media Rights article, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - MediaRights.org information, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Media Theory, Undated (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
  - Meeting agenda, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Meeting agenda, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Meeting notes, 1992-1999 (Box 3, Folder 35 - 36)
  - Meeting notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 32-34, Folder 34)
  - Meeting notes -- brainstorm, Undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Meeting notes -- Distribution Committee agenda, Undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Meeting notes -- skill sharing collaboration, Undated (Folder 2 Left)
  - Meeting notes -- strengths / weaknesses brainstorm, Undated (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Retreat Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Message Books, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
  - Middle East activist group contact list, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Middle East resources, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous administrative stuff, Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Mississippi Burning" contract, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Mixed photocopies, Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Mobilization for Global Justice literature, Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Moscoe, Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - National news media contact list, Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - NAMAC -- Resource guides and info, Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - New Movement -- Security response, Undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Newsletters -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper clippings, Undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Next Agenda, Undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - NFLCP members - 11/85, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Notebook -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 4, Folder 19)